# **Chris Flack**

+1765-760-4548 • chris.flack@hey.com • linkedin.com/in/ccflack

# **Senior Software Engineer**

Growth-minded Senior Software Engineer with more than 7 years experience in the SaaS startup world. An expert in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, with a passion for mentoring teams and intentional back-end development. Most recently found at The Juice, improving user engagement through data visualization and analysis, and providing tools to distill marketing content to key insights using AI tools.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# The Juice

Early stage B2B marketing content platform, focused on distribution, content insights, and user analytics.

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Jun 2023 - Jan 2024

- » Built a revenue attribution engine, connecting The Juice users to associated company entities in Salesforce and Hubspot, tying content engagement to revenue.
- » Analyzed audience engagement across multiple dimensions by creating the Persona Analytics feature, providing actionable insights to aid marketers in developing more targeted content strategies.
- » Built AI tooling to help content creators effectively communicate with audiences across a variety of media, reducing content consumption times by up to 90%, and improving user engagement.
- » Utilized the latest Rails releases and Hotwire Stack to maintain a cutting-edge codebase and clean, intentional back-end design, improving time-to-market for new features.

### **DriverReach**

A modern recruiting & compliance management system purpose-built for trucking and logistics companies.

### **Senior Software Engineer**

Mar 2022 - Mar 2023

- » Upgraded a legacy codebase through two major Rails versions. (5.0
   → 5.1 and 5.1 → 5.2).
- » Developed an adaptable, efficient Rails interface for HubSpot's API v3, reducing maintenance efforts by 50%, and improving integration performance by 20%.
- » Optimized Vue frontend with an intentional component structure, resulting in faster feature development and increased consistency and reliability in UI.
- » Championed adoption of remote pairing habits, collaborative review and approval processes, and consistent design philosophies to improve code quality and cross-domain knowledge sharing.

### **SKILLS**

Artificial Intelligence,
AWS, Backend Web
Development, Data
Access, Data
Visualization, Docker,
Documentation, Git,
Heroku, JavaScript,
Mentoring, PostgreSQL,
Redis, Ruby, Ruby on
Rails, Sidekiq, Software as
a Service, Stakeholder
Engagement, User
Engagement

JavaScript Frameworks: AngularJS, React, Vue

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor Of Arts B.A. in Religious Studies

Ball State University Dec 2010

# **Springbuk**

A platform that provides insights and opportunities from health benefits data to help employers and benefits advisors make datadriven decisions.

# **Senior Software Engineer**

May 2021 - Mar 2022

- » Boosted team morale and skill development by spearheading the first fully remote, cross-discipline mentorship program, teaching Rails basics to engineers from multiple teams.
- » Dockerized multiple applications for prod-like developer environments, and the lead team in adoption of this toolset, among many DevEx improvements.
- » Improved testing efficiency by developing ephemeral development environments, leading to a 30% decrease in bug resolution time and faster time-to-market for new features.
- » Lead the features team in early adoption of an in-house atomic Design System, built in React. Coordinated with the Design System team on implementation, distribution, and documentation.

# **Software Engineer**

Apr 2019 - May 2021

- » Implemented a middleware-level logging for HITRUST's required PHI access auditing, enabling easy monitoring of sensitive data access.
- » Back-end technical lead on the Timelines feature set, developing architecture and back-end design for a preventative health tracking and wellness measurement tool.

### Mobi

A mobile device management platform for enterprise scale device fleets.

### **Software Engineer**

Feb 2017 - Apr 2019

» Worked on development of the Workflow designer, a robust Business Process Management Notation GUI connected to the MOBI application and partner APIs.

# **VOLUNTEERING**

### **Brackets For Good**

Jan 2017 - Mar 2019

Volunteer Devleoper • Indianapolis, IN

- » Maintained and improved codebase for a fun, competitive web application gamifying philanthropic giving.
- » Monitored and responded to issues around critical go-live events during the platform's March Madness donation drive.

### **PRESENTATIONS**

**Level Up - Growth in Individuals, Teams, and Organizations** Jan 2019 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AehEQVkfT0E

Strong Parameters (& other fun party conversations)

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CbPTb\_4bVQw

Jun 2018